Now let's move onto the next method.
Agora vamos para o prximo mtodo.
So here we have this method called max, which
Ento, aqui temos esse mtodo chamado max, que retorna
returns the maximum of two numbers. How many execution
o mximo de dois nmeros. Quantos caminhos de execuo
paths do we have here? We have two execution paths. And that is
temos aqui? Ns temos dois caminhos de execuo. E isso
dependent upon this condition. So if
depende dessa condio. Ento, se A for
A is greater, we're going to return A, otherwise we're going to return B.
maior, vamos retornar A, caso contrrio, retornaremos B.
So there are two execution paths in this method. And the
Portanto, h dois caminhos de execuo nesse mtodo. E o nmero de
number of tests is often equal to or greater than
testes  geralmente igual ou maior que o
the number of execution paths. So, back in our test
nmero de caminhos de execuo. Ento, de volta
class, I'm going to create
nossa classe de teste, vou criar outro mtodo
another test method, test, public,
de teste, test, public, void, voc est testando
void, you're testing the max method. Now when anyone
o mtodo max. Agora quando
(?) write tests for a method, I would rather create all the test
algum (? ) escrever testes para um mtodo, prefiro criar
methods first before implementing them. I just want to brainstorm
todos os mtodos de teste antes de implement-los. Eu s quero debater todos os
all the different scenarios that need to be tested. This way
diferentes cenrios que precisam ser testados. Dessa forma, asseguro-me de
I make sure that I won't miss a scenario when I get busy writing the
que no vou perder um cenrio quando estiver
tests. So, the first scenario I want to test here is when
ocupado escrevendo os testes. Ento, o primeiro cenrio que quero testar aqui
the first argument is greater. So, first argument
quando o primeiro argumento  maior. Ento, o
is greater, it should return
primeiro argumento  maior, ele
the first argument.
deve retornar o primeiro argumento.
Now, I'm going to duplicate this,
Agora, vou duplicar isso,
the second scenario is where?
o segundo cenrio  onde?
The second argument is greater. So, second argument is greater
O segundo argumento  maior. Ento, segundo
and it should return
argumento  maior e
the second argument.
deve retornar o segundo argumento.
Now here we have a third scenario. Can you tell what
Agora aqui temos um terceiro cenrio. Voc pode dizer de que
scenario I'm talking about here? That is the scenario where the two
cenrio eu estou falando aqui? Esse  o cenrio em que
arguments are equal. Now, this is something that I want you to pay great
os dois argumentos so iguais. Agora, isso  algo que eu
attention to here. So far, in order to write
quero que voc preste muita ateno aqui. At agora, para escrever
tests, I started by looking at the implementation of method
testes, comecei examinando a implementao do mtodo
that I wrote tests based on this implementation.
que escrevi testes com base nessa implementao.
This is a good approach to get started, but it's not enough,
Esta  uma boa abordagem para comear, mas no  suficiente, no
it's not something that you should rely on. Because with this approach, when you
algo que voc deve confiar. Porque com essa abordagem, quando
write your tests based on implementation, it is possible
voc escreve seus testes com base na implementao,  possvel
that that implementation might have problems. Maybe your implementation
que essa implementao possa ter problemas. Talvez sua implementao esteja
is missing something. So you don't want to rely on that implementation.
faltando alguma coisa. Ento voc no quer confiar nessa implementao.
The best way to write test for method, is to think of it as a
A melhor maneira de escrever um teste para o mtodo
black box. Let's imagine we don't know what is inside the max
pensar nele como uma caixa preta. Vamos imaginar que no sabemos o
method. Max method is just one method that takes two
que est dentro do mtodo max. O mtodo Max  apenas um mtodo
arguments. A ending. What are different possibilities here?
que recebe dois argumentos. Um final. Quais so as diferentes possibilidades aqui?
One possibility is A is greater, another possibility
Uma possibilidade  A  maior, outra possibilidade  B
is B is greater, and the last possibility is their equal.
maior e a ltima possibilidade  a mesma.
So, I'm going to go back to our test class, duplicate
Ento, vou voltar para nossa aula de teste, duplicar o
the last test, and change the name of the test method.
ltimo teste e alterar o nome do mtodo de teste.
So, this scenario
Portanto, essa condio de
condition is arguments are equal
cenrio  argumentos iguais,
it should return the same argument.
devendo retornar o mesmo argumento.
Okay? Now, let's start
OK? Agora vamos
implementation. So first we should create
comear a implementao. Ento, primeiro devemos criar
an instance of the Math class. Math.
uma instncia da classe Math. Matemtica.
Now enact, call the Math method,
Agora decida, chame o mtodo Math, aqui o primeiro
here the first argument should be greater. So, I'm going to pass 2
argumento deve ser maior. Ento, eu vou passar
and 1. Get the result,
2 e 1. Obtenha o
and Assert. That
resultado e assert. Esse resultado
result, is equal to
igual a
2. Let's run this test.
2. Vamos rodar esse teste.
It's passing, beautiful.
Est passando, linda.
Now, the second test. To save time, I'm just going to copy
Agora, o segundo teste. Para economizar tempo, vou copiar essas
these few lines, but in the real world you shouldn't copy paste code, it's
poucas linhas, mas no mundo real voc no deve copiar o
better to write it from scratch, because sometimes when you copy paste code, you
cdigo,  melhor escrever do zero, porque s vezes quando voc
make mistakes. So, here I'm going to change these arguments
copia o cdigo, voc comete erros. Ento, aqui vou alterar esses
to 1 and 2. So the second argument is greater, and the
argumentos para 1 e 2. Portanto, o segundo argumento  maior e
Assertion should still be the same. And one last time,
a afirmao ainda deve ser a mesma. E uma ltima
Going to paste these few lines.
vez, indo colar essas poucas linhas.
And as the arguments I'm going to pass one and one
E como os argumentos vou passar um e um e afirmar
and Assert that result is equal to one. Now,
que resultado  igual a um. Agora, vou executar
I'm going to run all the tests in this class.
todos os testes nesta aula.
So I put my curser on the class name, right here,
Ento eu coloquei meu cursor no nome da classe, bem
and press command and T, and command and R.
aqui, e pressione command e T, e command e R.
So you can see, all the tests in this class
Ento voc pode ver, todos os testes nesta
are passing. Beautiful.
classe esto passando. Bonita.